

9.5 years of total IT experience with hands on experience in ServiceNow Development.



Current Designation: Senior Consultant Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Noida, Greater Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: servicenow, servicenow, service now, service now, Incident Management, Change Management, Problem

Management, Javascript

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Dec-20 Last Modified: 10-Nov-20

## **Summary**

8.5 years of diverse IT experience in Design, Analysis, Development & Enhancement.

Hands on experience of working as a ServiceNow Admin/Developer.

All kind of platform based scripting: business rules, client scripts, script includes, HTML, java script, UI actions, ACLs, Workflows Table, field creation and configuration. Dictionary, UI Policies, Application and Module, Email configuration, inbound actions.

Actively participated in ISO Audit and PCI Audit in Agile.

# **Work Experience**

Capgemini as Senior Consultant Dec 2019 to Till Date

**Wipro** as Associate Consultant Jul 2018 to Dec 2019

Working as ServiceNow Developer in ABB

**HCL Technologies Ltd.** as Senior Software Engineer -Application Programming Jul 2014 to Jun 2018

Project 1 ServiceNow- LexisNexis from Reed Elsevier, USA

Role ServiceNow Admin/Developer Tools / Technology ServiceNow

Job Responsibilities Perform core configuration tasks including system policies, business rules, Script Include and client scripts.

Manage users, groups and roles

Manage data with Tables, Import Sets, and Update Sets.

Create Workflow activities and approvals. Implement new workflows that use a variety of activities to understand how records are generated from workflows

Perform migration activities Dev to QA, QA to Prod

Develop and improve user systems procedures, and prepares systems documentation.

Establish and maintain effective communications with customers, other technology specialists, and vendors about services.

Managing client scripts, UI policies, UI actions

Moving data in and out of an instance using import sets and transform maps and auto import of data into service now.

Maintain existing applications. Create code that meets system standards.

Migration of customizations from one instance to another instance.

Ongoing Maintenance.

Develop and manage application code, user interface

Develop necessary development documentation as needed e.g. technical design, developer notes, etc.

#### Project 2 LexisNexis from Reed Elsevier, USA

LexisNexis® is a leading global provider of content-enabled workflow solutions designed specifically for professionals in the legal, risk management, corporate, government, law enforcement, accounting, and academic markets. LexisNexis originally pioneered online information with its Lexis® and Nexis® services. Part of Reed Elsevier, LexisNexis Legal & Professional serves customers in more than 175 countries with 10,000 employees worldwide.

Software Developer

Tools / Technology Interwoven Teamsite 7.2, C#.Net, SQL Server, Visual Studio 2008, Windows XP, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Perl, VSS6.0, XSL, Livesite.

Job Responsibilities Developed the website using Interwoven Teamsite 7.2,8.2

Participated in requirements gathering activities interfacing with business users for gathering initial business requirements

Responsible for code review and validating the functionality as per business requirements Responsible for making âjQuery11100476291557915262\_1527594669331user

controlsâjQuery111008197859539886039\_1528565691793 using Visual Studio

Implementing the controls on the websites

Maintain database through Teamsite using ipls, Sql Server.

Handle projects with other vendor partners

Responsible for Unit testing post deployment in every environment to make sure that release is up to standard.

Share daily status of task/updates

Provide leadership and direction for day to day operational support

Own day to day production environment stability and availability

Proactively identify potential issues and drive resolution to avoid user impact and facilitate continuous improvement

Identify opportunities for improvement and make constructive suggestions for change

Monitor, control and manage all areas of a project phase.

#### Applied Electro Magnetics Pvt Ltd. as Software Engineer

Apr 2011 to Jul 2014

Project CEL's MSDAC, SSDAC, HASSDAC

Software Developer Role

Tools/Technology C#.NET, C, VC++6.0, Visual Studio 2008, MySQL

Job Responsibilities Provide problem-solving and technical support for Production systems and troubleshoot and provide root cause analysis.

Participate in version releases and application software patches

Test & ensure availability of critical production systems during business hours after builds, bug fixes and patching Support Functional testing and UAT

Support implementation of new enhancements

Conduct analysis and do bug fixes for production incidents.

Carry out daily health-check activities involving application checks, system checks, and database checks and related on production systems / servers.

Act as a liaison between business and technology groups to facilitate communication both ways

Conduct stakeholder interviews to gather business requirements

Write complete business requirements and facilitate sign-off

Support tracking of bugs/enhancements/features as part of the change management process

Software Installation and testing

#### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Maths) from Veer Bahadur Singh Purvanchal University (VBSPU) in 2007

PG: MCA (Computers) from Gautam Buddha Technical University, Lucknow in 2011

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
ServiceNow	Mardid	2019	4 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
HTML, XML		2018	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
JavaScript		2018	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi	Expert			
English	Expert			

## **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time